mondosol.com 2013-05-09

# 

PRIVACY POLICY

Date: March 26th, 2011  
Welcome to Mondosol.com ("Site"), an online service designed to provide language, computer learning content, language, computer learning curriculum, and to facilitate language exchanges and foreign language practice. Mondosol.com is owned and operated by Mondosol, and is committed to safeguarding your privacy, and this privacy policy explains our data collection, use, and disclosure practices. If you have specific questions about these practices, please contact us by email at [support@mondosol.com](mailto:support@mondosol.com).

1\. Information collected

When you register with Mondosol.com, you provide us with certain personal information, such as your name, your email address, your spoken and learning languages, your gender, and any other personal or prefer-ence information that you enter.

When you use Mondosol.com, you may set up your personal profile, form relationships, send messages, per-form searches and queries, enroll in events and courses, and transmit information through various chan-nels. We collect this information so that we can provide you the service and offer personalized features. In most cases, we retain it so that, for instance, you can return to view prior messages you have sent or easily see your friend list.

You can choose not to provide this information to us, but in general some information about you is required in order for you to register and participate in the features offered through the Site.

If you choose to use our invitation service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend an email inviting him or her to visit the site. Mondosol.com may attempt to send invitations more than once. Mondosol.com stores this information to send email, to register a friend connection if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [support@mondosol.com](mailto:support@mondosol.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

We automatically collect some information about your computer when you visit the Site. For example, we will collect your IP address, Web browser software (such as Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer), and referring web site. We also may collect information about your activity on this Site, such as the courses in which you enroll. One of our goals in collecting this automatic information is to help improve your user experience.

Finally, when you visit the Site, we may assign your computer a "cookie" (a small, unique identifier text file) to remember who you are. For example, if you register on the Site, we may record your username in a cookie for verification purposes. We also may include other information in our cookie files; for example, if you arrived at our Site via a link from third party site, we may include the URL of the linking page.

2\. Use of personal Information

Mondosol finds it very important to ensure that all of the consumer's personal information is treated with the utmost care and security and according to the Italian Data Protection Act. Mondosol will not give the consumer's personal information to third parties, except when the information is required for the services that Mondosol provides to the consumer or when necessary for the delivery of an order, or when legally obliged/upon request of the authorities. Records of Mondosol's website visits are kept for statistical purposes. Information concerning the amount of visitors and visitor frequency to the website of Mondosol will be used for internal research and website improvement. However, this general information is anonymous and cannot be traced back to the individual visitor.

The personal data that Mondosol collects about its members and users shall be carefully and adequately processed. To process an consumer's order and/or information Mondosol will ask the consumer for its personal data when the consumer registers for a purchase (this will include name, date of birth, e-mail and postal address). A consumer will need to give Mondosol its consent before any processing takes place and its personal data will only be used for the purposes stated in these terms and conditions and or at the point of collection. Mondosol is committed to maintaining the highest standards of personal data protection and will not collect information about a consumer without its consent.

By using Mondosol's website a consumer expressly gives his consent to Mondosol for:

1\. Processing personal data so that Mondosol can efficiently provide the consumer with information about new features and services available on the website;  
2\. Processing personal data to enhance Mondosol's services available to the members;  
3\. Transferring such personal data to offices located in The Netherlands for the purposes of processing by Mondosol;  
4\. Using cookies (see below)

In order to measure the success of Mondosol's online advertising, Mondosol use pixels, or transparent GIF files, to establish which of Mondosol's online adverts successfully bring people to it's website or the sites of Mondosol's affiliates. The GIF files are provided by third parties who provide Mondosol with online advertising analysis. This system places a cookie on Mondosol's browser when a consumer enters Mondosol's website via an online advert allowing Mondosol to see which online adverts bring Mondosol the most visitors to its website. The information collected on Mondosol's behalf, is anonymous and does not personally identify the consumer. The information does not contain the consumers name, address, telephone number or e-mail address. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but a consumer can change its browser to reject them. Even without a cookie a consumer can still use Mondosol's website. If a consumer would like to know how to opt-out of the technologies mentioned above the consumer can contact Mondosol's helpdesk.

A consumer may be contacted by Mondosol from time to time in relation to the products and services offered by Mondosol.

3\. Disclosure of personal information

Unless legally required to do so Mondosol will not share personal data of the consumer with any third parties, who are not mentioned in this clause, without the prior consent of the consumer.

4\. Access to Personal Information

A consumer can amend its details by itself by signing in to "Your Account" or it can notify Mondosol's customer services if the consumer wishes to remove or have changes made to its personal data.

5\. Your Choices With Respect To The Collection and Use of Personal Information

A consumer can notify Mondosol's customer services if the Consumer wishes to remove or have changes made to his or her processed personal data.

6\. Security

While no web site can guarantee security, Mondosol has implemented appropriate administrative, technical, and physical security procedures to help protect personal information. For example, only authorized employees are permitted to access personal information, and they only may do so for permitted business functions.

7\. Third party websites

Web sites to which this Site links do not operate under this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you examine the privacy statements posted on those other web sites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.

8\. Third party advertising

Advertisements that appear on Mondosol.com are sometimes delivered (or "served") directly to users by third party advertisers. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. These third party adver-tisers may also download cookies to your computer, or use other technologies such as JavaScript and "web beacons" (also known as "1x1 gifs") to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. Doing this allows the advertising network to recognize your computer each time they send you an advertisement in order to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. In this way, they may compile information about where individuals using your computer or browser saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked. Mondosol.com does not have access to or control of the cookies that may be placed by the third party advertisers. Third party advertisers have no access to your contact information stored on Mondosol.com unless you choose to share it with them.   
This privacy policy covers the use of cookies by Mondosol.com and does not cover the use of cookies or other tracking technologies by any of its advertisers.

9\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

Mondosol may update this Privacy Policy in the future to reflect changes in our privacy practices, our website functionality, or applicable legislation, so please check back often. We will notify you about mate-rial changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us or by placing a prominent notice on the Site.

10\. How you can contact us

If you have questions about this privacy policy, please e-mail us at [support@mondosol.com](mailto:support@mondosol.com). You may request a copy or send a correction of the personal information we hold about you by contacting the Privacy Officer at [privacyofficer@mondosol.com](mailto:privacyofficer@mondosol.com) or writing to:  
Mondosol   
c/o HIBU Ringerike Grunderhage, Bredalsveien 14   
3511 Hønefoss   
Norway
